Rellie R. Balagat | Full-Stack Web Developer



86-A Tandang Sora Avenue Quezon City



09069121383



relliebalagat@gmail.com



github.com/rellierb



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Self-motivated and passionate Full-Stack Web Developer experienced on project management, system analysis and design, web application security, quality assurance, and machine learning concepts where I can apply my skills and knowledge on meeting and exceeding company's needs.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Full Stack Web Developer

Emerson | January 2022 - Present

Job Description:

- Acts as Senior Technical Lead within the team that provides guidance to the team in aspect of web application development and design
- Lead the development on projects and coordinates with customers and management on ensuring timely delivery of projects
- Creates and establishes improvement on the development process including project and technical documentation, web application security, Dev Ops and quality assurance.
- Introduce, research, and implement new technology, architecture and tools

Web Developer

Emerson | Oct 2018 - December 2021

Job Description:

- Support Groups:
 - Enterprise IT (April 2021 Present)
 - Middle East and Africa Automation Solutions (Feb 2020 April 2021)
 - o Automation Solutions Research and Insights team (August 2019 January 2020)
 - o Supply Chain Resource Center (Oct 2019 July 2020)
- Performs business requirement gathering, provides development estimate and proper implementation
- Implements change request based on client specification
- Creates highly maintainable systems using .Net Framework and Office 365 Applications (SharePoint, PowerApps, PowerAutomate)
- Troubleshoots, fixes, and resolves minor and major bugs/issues
- Creates reports and dashboard based on client specification using Power BI

- Conducts User Acceptance Testing with clients
- Provides support to clients

Security Researcher | Bug Bounty Hunter

Bugcrowd | Feb 2021 - Jun 2021

Job Description:

• Performs manual security testing on public bug bounty programs

Junior Web Developer

Emerson | July 2018 - Sept 2018

Job Description:

- Analyzes business requirements, provide development estimates and implementation
- Develops modules and site functionalities
- Troubleshoots, fixes, and resolves minor and major bugs/issues
- Performs testing on internal sites

Bookkeeper

Landbank of the Philippines | July 2015 - September 2016

Job Description:

- Prepares and processes reports to be submitted to Bureau of Internal Revenue
- Remits consolidated reports on daily collection of Landbank to Bureau of Internal Revenue
- Prepares letters and memorandums to Landbank Branches

Customer Service Representative - Teller

Metrobank Trust and Company | September 2014 - January 2015

Job Description:

- Processes banking transactions from clients
- Prepares reports of daily banking transactions
- Cross sells products and services to clients

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

- Web Application Security Attacks (OWASP Top 10)
- Web Vulnerability Scanner (Burp Suite, OWASP ZAP)
- Programming Languages (C#, JavaScript, Java, PHP, Ruby, Python, C/C++)
- Network Protocol Analyzer (Wireshark)
- Project Tracker Tool (JIRA, Azure Boards)
- Databases (MSSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB)
- Operating Systems (Linux, Windows)
- Backend Frameworks (.Net Framework, Laravel, Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, Django)

- Frontend Frameworks (ReactJS, Angular, VueJS)
- Microsoft Technologies (SharePoint, PowerBI, Nintex Workflow and Forms, PowerAutomate, PowerApps)
- Versioning Control System (Git)

SKILLS

- Able to effectively self-manage independent software development projects
- Highly demonstrated research and analytical skills
- Great communication and presentation skills
- Able to work and collaborate in a team setting
- Knowledgeable in web application attacks and remediation
- Highly experienced on designing systems and databases
- Worked on applying new coding architecture and introducing new technology and frameworks to the systems development process
- Competent in technical writing and documenting project details
- Passionate on computer security research
- Knowledgeable in networking and machine learning concepts

PROJECTS

COMPANY

Organization Announcement

- Employee organization movements are announced and posted to Enterprise IT HR site after the requests go through the dynamic approval process.
- Technologies used: Microsoft PowerApps and PowerAutomate

Full-Time Remote Work

- Formalized the approval of individual roles for fully remote work within Enterprise IT.

 Approval goes up to CIO with justification from line managers on behalf of their team.
- Technologies used: Microsoft PowerApps and PowerAutomate

Automated Scorecard Report

- Developed the Training module where Human Resource Center Heads and Business Partners could upload their respective training for assigned location and track the total hour counts and list of employee trainings.
- Technologies used: ASP.Net MVC, C#, MSSQL, JQuery, CSS, HTML

Capability Scorecard

- Developed the managers dashboard where users could dynamically filter the Power BI report of respective team based on selected values.
- Technologies used: ASP.Net MVC, C#, MSSQL, JQuery, CSS, HTML

Automation Tools

- Creating Employee Records in SharePoint list via Excel
 - Synching of newly created MEA Employee records stored in Excel file and SharePoint list. Human Resource Analyst receives summary reports on newly added employee records upon flow trigger.
 - o Technologies used: Microsoft PowerAutomate
- Removing old data in Employee Records in SharePoint list via Excel
 - Finding MEA Employee records in SharePoint list that are not existing in the Employee record excel file. Human Resource Analyst receives report summary upon flow trigger.
 - o Technologies used: Microsoft PowerAutomate
- Expiring and Expired Guarantee Notification
 - Sending of weekly individual notifications to requestors and summary report to approvers on expiring guarantees within 90 days.
 - Sending of monthly individual notifications to requestors and summary report to approvers on expired guarantees.
 - o Technologies used: Microsoft PowerAutomate

Delegation of Authority

- A form for filing of project signing limits with approval process.
- Technologies used: Microsoft PowerApps and PowerAutomate

Existing Oracle Request Form

- A form for modification of Oracle request details for Middle East and Africa Automation Solution employees. Requests undergo 5-step layer of approval process. Global ITSS is informed upon request approval completion.
- Technologies used: Microsoft PowerApps and PowerAutomate

New Oracle Request Form

- Filing and requesting of new Oracle number for Middle East and Africa Automation Solution employees. Requests undergo 5-step layer of approval process. Global ITSS is informed upon request approval completion.
- Technologies used: Microsoft PowerApps and PowerAutomate

Maintenance Request Form

- A form where Middle East and Africa Automation Solution employees report
 opportunities or file for request in different Middle East Emerson campuses. Notifications
 will be forwarded to employees after request have been completed by approvers.
- Technologies used: SharePoint, JavaScript, Nintex Forms and Workflow

Bank Guarantee Amendment Form

- A separate form for amending the Bank Guarantee items informing approvers that go through approval process.
- Technologies used: SharePoint, Nintex New Responsive Forms and Workflow

Bank Guarantee Form

- A form where Middle East and Africa Automation Solution from Finance and different Business Units file for New Bank Guarantee. Bank Guarantee items go through 2-step approval process.
- Technologies used: SharePoint, Nintex New Responsive Forms and Workflow

Telephony Reimbursement Form

- A form where Middle East and Africa Automation Solution employees file their monthly telephone reimbursement. IT Telephony team receives notification upon filing in the form.
- Technologies used: SharePoint, JavaScript, Nintex Forms and Workflow

Research and Insight Project Tracker

- A centralized repository for the R&I team that will help them to easily monitor the status, files and reports of each project.
- A ticketing system where project and research leads are being updated for every new project that the team had initiated.
- Dashboard using Power BI for tracking and monitoring the status of projects.
- Technologies used: SharePoint, Power BI, Nintex Forms and Workflow

SCRC Request for Quotation Validation Tool

- Internal website where clients validate their respective request for quotation (RFQ) and updates the administrator of such validation.
- Data Ingestion module with validation of Excel files
- A report generating tool used by administrator for decision making.
- Dashboard using JavaScript for tracking and monitoring status of RFQs
- Technologies used: ASP.Net MVC, C#, MSSQL, JQuery, CSS, HTML

SCRC Ticketing

- A ticketing tool where managers will ask for a specific work task from employees
- Technologies used: SharePoint, Power BI, Nintex Forms and Workflow

Visitor Workflow

- A system where employees could file and track their request to different support groups that will manage the employees' visitor requirement.
- Workflow that approves and tracks visitor's requirement stay here in Philippines.
- Technologies used: .Net framework, C#, MSSQL, JQuery, CSS, HTML

BOOTCAMP PROJECTS

Book Repository

- An online e-commerce website for books.
- Technologies used: PHP, CSS, HTML, MySQL, JavaScript

Meower

- A question-and answer website similar Quora
- Technologies used: Laravel, CSS, HTML, MySQL, JQuery

OTHER PROJECTS

Tagpros.us

- An online course platform where instructors can create courses on their preferred topics
- Technologies used: React, NodeJS, PostgreSQL

Klir Resort, Coralview Beach Resort and Amanantez Beach Resort Reservation System

- A resort reservation system with booking, payment, and reporting functionality
- Technologies used: PHP, MySQL, JQuery

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Completed 56 units November 2016 - March 2018 University of the East, Manila

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration Major in Business Management

June 2010 - April 2014 University of the East, Manila

Certifications

Certified SAFe 5 Practitioner, Scaled Agile Framework

January 2022 – January 2023

TRAININGS

Scaled Agile Framework

January 2021

Microsoft PowerBI

September 2019

Full-Stack Web Development Training

October 2017 - May 2018 Zuitt Coding Bootcamp

ORGANIZATION

Leader, Documentation Division

July 2017 - March 2018 UE-CCSS Research and Development Unit

ACHIEVEMENTS

University Scholar

November 2017 - March 2018

University President Scholar

June 2017 - October 2017

Civil Service Examination Passer - Professional Level

E. Rodriguez Elementary School, April 2014

Leadership Award

UE Manila EVSAP - March 2014

REFERENCES

Will be provided upon request